Henry C. Smith papers, Inclusive: 1918, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Henry C. Smith papers
Inclusive: 1918, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3784
Smith, Henry C., 1896 -
1 document box
The Henry C. Smith papers consist of letters and a few photographs recounting Smith’s daily experiences in the United States Army in flight cadet training school in Ithaca, New York; Dallas, Texas; and Waco, Texas during World War I.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
Henry C. Smith was born in 1896 March. In 1918, he enlisted in the United States Army, intending to train as a pilot. He first entered cadet training school in 1918 April at Cornell University in Ithaca, New York. In July, he was transferred to continue his ground training at Camp Dick near Dallas, Texas. In September, he was assigned to Rich Field in Waco, Texas where he continued flight training until the war ended. After being discharged circa 1918 December, Smith return home to Pennsylvania where he remained for several years. By 1930, he was married to Ann Smith and had moved from Wilkinsburg, Pennsylvania, to East Washington, Pennsylvania. By 1940, he had moved to Ohio. The date and location of his death are unknown.
Scope and Content
The Henry C. Smith papers consist of materials from 1918, with some undated items. The papers are correspondence from Smith to his mother in Pennsylvania, Sarah Jane Miller Smith, recounting his experiences training to be a pilot in the United States Army during World War I.
Series I, Correspondence, consists of outgoing correspondence from Smith along with a few photographs, a postcard, and a printed copy of a poem.
Arrangement
The collection arrived in a cardboard box. The letters were organized chronologically although some letters were out of sequence. The folder titles identified the month of the letters they contained as well as listing the number of letters and pages. Some letters were bookmarked by strips of yellow paper with short notes or symbols written in red ink.
The collection largely retains its original order. Letters that were out of sequence were moved to their correct chronological position. Folder titles were simplified to just the name of the month, omitting the unlabeled numbers identifying how many letters and pages each folder contained. Envelopes were copied before being deaccessioned.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3784.
Related Resources
Related references
U.S. Bureau of the Census. 1900 United States Federal Census, s.v. “Henry Conway Smith,” Pittsburgh Ward 16, Allegheny, Pennsylvania. Heritage Quest Online, Accessed 2020 November 30.
U.S. Bureau of the Census. 1910 United States Federal Census, s.v. “Henry C Smith,” Pittsburgh Ward 10, Allegheny, Pennsylvania. Heritage Quest Online, Accessed 2020 November 30.
U.S. Bureau of the Census. 1930 United States Federal Census, s.v. “Henry C Smith,” East Washington, Washington, Pennsylvania, USA, Accessed 2020 November 30.
U.S. Bureau of the Census. 1940 United States Federal Census, s.v. “Henry C Smith,” Wooster, Wayne, Ohio. Heritage Quest Online, Accessed 2020 November 30.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
United States. Army -- Officers -- Training of -- Texas -- Waco.; United States. Army. Air Service.
Places
Rich Field (Waco, Tex.)
Subjects
World War, 1914-1918 -- United States.
Genres
Personal correspondence.
- Correspondence, 1918; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  Series I, Correspondence, consists of outgoing correspondence from Smith along with a few photographs, a postcard, and a printed copy of a poem. The series is in average condition.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Photographic print; Postcards
  - Letters, 1918 April 12-May 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters, 1918 May 1-26, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters, 1918 June 2-29, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters, 1918 July 2-31 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters, 1918 August 1-28, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters, 1918 September 2-29, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters, 1918 October 2-27, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters, 1918 November 2-December 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General, 1918 June 20, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)